MAX BEHRENS BSc, PGDE

Netherby West, Otley Road, Menston, West Yorkshire, LS29 6EE Mobile: 07513 944101, Landline: 01943 874931

maxdbehrens@gmail.com · <u>linkedin.com</u> · <u>maxbehrens.com</u>

I am a graduate in mathematics and computer science from the University of Liverpool with a passion for data modelling and software engineering.

I am currently studying a Post-Graduate Diploma in Further and Post-Compulsory Education at Liverpool Hope University, and am broadening my skillset in teaching within my field.

I bring to each new project a love of problem solving, a commitment to extracting knowledge from unstructured data, and during my GCSE and A-Level teaching experience have established a skill for conveying mathematical concepts to students of different ages.

I have undertaken commercial work building and configuring customer databases, including relational management sites in WordPress for more effective ways of viewing company data and connecting with employees. My teacher training has equipped me to convey complex ideas in simple terms; and I have produced statistical analyses for clients, using data mining and visualization in Tableau.

EXPERIENCE

JUL 2021 - PRESENT

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER VERVE DIGITAL

Utilising PHP and MySQL along with JS and CSS, I have developed transactional websites and apps for clients' employees to more easily manage their appointments and company data.

SEPT 2020 - JUL 2021

MATHEMATICS AND COMPUTER SCIENCE TEACHER, LIVERPOOL HOPE UNIVERSITY/ UTC WARRINGTON

I am taking a post graduate diploma in education, specialising in post compulsory training and involving practical teaching placements. My work has included supervising, planning and conducting classes from years 10 to 13, specifically teaching Maths at GCSE and A-Level, as well as BTEC computer science.

NOV 2017 - NOV 2020

PRIVATE TUTOR. LIVERPOOL ACADEMY INTERNATIONAL

Mathematics, computer science, physics and chemistry tutor at Academy International private tutoring agency, teaching classes with students studying from GCSE to A-level. In working here I have learnt valuable communication skills such as presenting points clearly and coming to new understandings and conclusions about the topics taught.

JUNE 2018 - NOV 2020

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER, LIVERPOOL ACADEMY INTERNATIONAL

I developed an online management database for my employer created using the PHP Laravel framework, which gave them a new, more efficient and accessible way to view and manage and query their company's data, such as contact information and class schedules. I have also developed a transactional website for the company.

EDUCATION

SEPT 2020 – JUL 2021

POST GRADUATE DIPLOMA OF EDUCATION IN FURTHER EDUCATION

LIVERPOOL HOPE UNIVERSITY (MERIT)

I have taught Maths, Physics & Computer Science GCSE and A-Level across Merseyside for my teacher training course with Liverpool Hope University.

SEPT 2017 - JUL 2020

MATHEMATICS AND COMPUTER SCIENCE BSc (JOINT HONOURS),

UNIVERSITY OF LIVERPOOL (SECOND CLASS HONOURS)

My degree has taught me to handle data and process computations efficiently; combating problems that arise with logical and effective methodology. I have completed projects in multiple programming languages and development kits such as Flutter and React, and have utilized software such as MATLAB to interpret dynamical systems and populations.

JUN 2017

GCE A- LEVELS, PRINCE HENRY'S GRAMMAR SCHOOL, OTLEY

Mathematics, Chemistry, Physics, Further Maths and Economics (AS).

JUN 2015

GCSEs, PRINCE HENRY'S GRAMMAR SCHOOL, OTLEY

A/A* grades in 12 subjects, including Maths, English, Triple Science, French, German, History.

SKILLS

- Website development in PHP, JS and C#.
- Photoshop and Gimp graphic design.
- Creating web applications using PHP frameworks.
- Experience using frameworks such as Flutter.
- Mathematical Modelling, MATLAB.

- Relational Database development in MySQL.
- Data visualization, Tableau, Power BI.
- WordPress design and development.
- Website development in WordPress
- Maths and computer science teaching experience.

ACTIVITIES

Participant in an international scheme organized by the Leeds Development Education Centre, where I was able to meet students from across the continent to discuss climate change issues.

Selected as one of the 10 finalists to run for a position in the UK Youth Parliament, where I delivered a speech to a large audience to propose my ideas for improvement and change within the party.

Designed computer graphics for various artists and websites using Adobe Photoshop and After Effects, teaching me to manage projects and work towards deadlines.

Singer, guitarist and pianist for three bands, one of which came first place in a charity competition.